Why not carry on her good work?
I enjoyed English, biology and chemistry at school.
But which one should I choose to study at university?
I did not know the answer until one evening when I sat down at the computer
to do some research on great women of China.
By chance I came across an article about a doctor called Lin Qiaozhi,
a specialist in women’s diseases.
She lived from 1901 to 1983.
One of them caught my eye.
It was a small book explaining how to cut the death rate from having
and caring for babies.
She gave some simple rules to follow for keeping babies clean,
healthy and free from sickness.
Why did she write that?
Who were the women that Lin Qiaozhi thought needed this advice?
I looked carefully at the text and realized that it was intended
for women in the countryside.
Perhaps if they had an emergency they could not reach a doctor.
Suddenly it hit me how difficult it was for a woman to get medical training at
that time.
That was a generation when girls’ education was always placed second to boys’.
Was she so much cleverer than anyone else?
Further reading made me realize that it was hard work and determination as well as her gentle nature
that got her into medical school.
What made her succeed later on was the kindness and consideration she showed to all her patients.
There was story after story of how Lin Qiaozhi,
tired after a day’s work, went late at night to deliver a baby
for a poor family who could not pay her.
By now I could not wait to find out more about her.
I discovered that Lin Qiaozhi had devoted her whole life to her patients
and had chosen not to have a family of her own.
Instead she made sure that about 50,000 babies were safely delivered.
By this time I was very excited.
Why not study at medical college like Lin Qiaozhi and carry on her good work?
It was still not too late for me to improve my studies,
prepare for the university entrance examinations,
and….